Kimberley Dobney

FRONT END/UX ENGINEER

Profile





As a methodical front-end developer with a design background, I've dedicated the last two years to Dyson as a UX engineer. Specializing in front-end development for IoT products and web apps, I excel at swiftly translating designer concepts into functional code. Proficient in JavaScript and UX concepts, I've played a pivotal role in improving collaboration between developers and designers. I've designed user trials, implemented their results and presented my work to stakeholders. Here's my portfolio, I'm unable to share my work at Dyson due to NDA's however I'm working on some playful freelance projects which I will add soon.

Previous Employment

UX Engineer

Dyson

March 2022 - Jan 2024

- Developed and deployed web apps using JS, HTML, CSS, JSX, and Framer.
- Worked within Agile Scrum teams and version-controlled code using Git.
- Conducted user trials with A/B testing and optimised interfaces from the results.
- Debugged remotely for international teams.
- Created responsive embedded rigs in Python and C++, using controller boards such as Arduinos and Raspberry Pi.
- Developed reusable interface prototyping tools using statemachines allowing designers to prototype quicker.

Brand Developer

WASE

August 2020 - July 2021

- Worked alongside external developers to improve the accessibility of the site, the SEO and the UX of the CTAs.
- Redesigned internal and external brand presence using Adobe Creative Cloud.
- Liaised with stakeholders and taught employees how to implement the new brand package.



Turn and Flow

August 2019 - November 2021

- Developed a product-service system to incorporate menstrual waste into mainstream composting systems.
- Optimised our site and social presence allowing us to crowdfund £23k for a study at Cranfield University.
- Developed our brand and video content using Adobe Creative Cloud as well as coding custom elements for our Squarespace website.

Related Experiece

- Volunteer Instructor at IO academy teaching JS.
- Participated in SOFTER Digital Futures festival in Copenhagen.
- · Attended Peckham Digital to gain insight into diversifying working practices and improving code-design collaboration as a Developer.
- Participated in an 8-hour Hackathon at Dyson creating an anonymous React Mood tracking App.
- Delivered workshops to year 8 students as part of the James Dyson Foundation.

Education

Full Stack Software iO Academy

Development A four-month intensive Bootcamp in full-stack software development.

Product Design Brunel University London (2:1)

Engineering BSc A three-year degree with one year model making placement.

Professional Achievements

Certified Scrum Master 2021 - Scrum Alliance Oatly Je Ne Sais Quis Award - Turn and Flow 2020 D&AD side-hustle awards finalist - For Turn and Flow's creative direction and branding







